In terms of designing
content architectures,
one of the ideas
that really help is
using a one-by-one convolution.
Now, you might be wondering,
what does a one-by-one
convolution do?
Isn't that just
multiplying by numbers.
That seems like a
funny thing to do.
Turns out it's not
quite like that.
Let's take a look. Here's
a one-by-one filter.
I put a number 2 there.
If you take this
six-by-six image,
six by six by one,
and convolve it with this
one-by-one-by-one filter,
you end up just taking the
emission multiplied by two.
So 1, 2, 3 ends up being 2,
4, 6, and so on.
A convolution by a
one-by-one filter
doesn't seem
particularly useful.
You just multiply
it by some number.
But that's the case of six by
six by one channel images.
If you have a six-by-six
by 32 instead of by one,
then a convolution with
a one-by-one filter can do
something that makes
much more sense.
In particular, what a
one-by-one convolution
will do is it will look
at each of the 36
different positions here.
It will take the
element-wise product between
32 numbers on the left and
the 32 numbers in the filter,
and then apply a ReLU,
nonlinearity to it after that.
To look at one of
the 36 positions,
maybe one slice
through this volume,
you take these 36 numbers,
multiply it by one
by one slice through
the volume like
that and you end up
with a single real number.
Which then gets plotted in
one of the outputs like that.
In fact, one way to think about
the 32 numbers you
have in this one,
a one by 32 filter
is as if you have
one neuron that is taking
us input 32 numbers.
Multiplying each of
these 32 numbers
in one slice in
the same position,
height, and width, but these
32 different channels,
multiplying them by 32 weights.
In applying a ReLU,
nonlinearity to it and then
outputting the corresponding
thing over there.
More generally, if you
have not just one filter,
but if you have
multiple filters,
then it's as if you
have not just one unit,
but multiple units to taking
as input all the numbers in
one slice and then building
them up into an output,
the 0.66 by six by
number of filters.
One way to think about a
one-by-one convolution
is that it is basically having
a fully connected neural network
that applies to each of the
62 different positions.
What that fully
connected neural network
does is it inputs
32 numbers and outputs
number of filters, outputs.
I guess the payer notation,
this is really a nc of 0 plus
1 if that's the next layer.
By doing those at each
of the 36 positions,
each of the six
by six positions,
you end up with
an output that is
six-by-six by the
number of filters.
This can carry out
a pretty non-trivial computation
on your input volume.
This idea is often called
a one-by-one convolution,
but it's sometimes also
called network in network.
It's described in this
paper by M. Lin, Q. Chen, S. Yan.
Even though the details of
the architecture in
this paper on views YZ,
this idea of a
one-by-one convolution
of this sometimes called
network and network
idea has been very
influential as
influence many other neural
network architectures,
including the inception network
which we'll see you
in the next video.
But to give you an
example of where
one-by-one convolution
is useful,
here's something you
could do with it.
Let's say you have a 28
by 28 by 192 volume.
If you want to shrink
the height and width,
you can use a pooling layer,
so we know how to do that.
But one of the number of
channels has gotten too big
and you want to shrink that.
How do you shrink it to a 28 by
28 by 32 dimensional volume?
Well, what you can do is use,
32 filters that are one-by-one,
and technically each
filter would be of
dimension one by one by 192,
because the number of
channels in your filter
has to match the number of
channels in your input volume.
But you use 32 filters
and the output
of this process will be
28 by 28 by 32 volume.
This is a way to let your
strength and see as well.
Whereas pooling layer
are used just to
shrink an h and nw,
the height and width
of these volumes.
We'll see later how this idea of
one-by-one convolutions
allows you
to shrink the number of channels
and therefore save on
computation in some networks.
But of course, if you want to
keep the number of channels
to the 192, that's fine too.
The effect of a
one-by-one convolution
is it just has nonlinearity.
It allows you to learn
a more complex function of
your network by
adding another layer,
the inputs 20 by 20 by 192,
and outputs 20 by 20 by 192.
You've now seen how
a one-by-one
convolution operation
is actually doing a pretty
non-trivial operation
and allows you to shrink
the number of channels in
your volumes or keep it the
same or even increase
it if you want.
In the next video,
you see that this can be used
to help build up to
the inception network.
Let's go onto the next video.